hello my name is stylist and courting
and I will present very briefly how data
mining works however most of the times
when people search about data mining
what they are interested is in the whole
process in which data mining is just in
one step so this video could be called
how-to knowledge discovery in databases
works this is the real title of this
video and to show how acknowledge
discovering databases works we present
these steps that starts from raw data
until we got the acknowledge about the
data that we have and when we do this
using our tools computational and
algorithm tools we start from the raw
data and obtain what we can call
knowledge the first step is from data
raw data to target beta so this is what
we call the selection of data suppose we
have lots of information about a certain
phenomena and we want to to derive some
knowledge about this in this case
sometimes we have data that is not
useful some data that is not ready to be
used
in a different format enos in this very
basic processing that we have to do is
color selection then we get data to the
target date with with this target data
we can do a prayer processing of this
target data one of the important
operations that we do here is to detect
for example outliers suppose we have
this chawl variable here in this data
distribution we can see or we can use
also algorithms to detect that that red
point is an outlier and in some cases
some algorithms may not work properly if
we have data which is very different
from the entire distribution so this is
called an outlier we can try to remove
these and get this processed data
without the
fliers another thing that we have that
we can do here is to detect missing
values suppose we have this data
distribution here we can use some
algorithms to estimate what could be
that two holes that we have here suppose
that we have this estimation using that
green line so we could try to
interpolate the other data in order to
see what could be the data in that holes
these are two of the most well known
pre-processing steps that are performing
our data independent of the application
we are doing after this we have to apply
the transformation of the data one thing
that we used to do in this case is to
normalize the date because sometimes we
have data that were eyes from 0 to 1
another data that is a textual data in
the other data we have four eyes from 0
to plus infinite most of the algorithms
they are created to use data in a
similar way one of the steps is to
normalize another step is to find
correlated variables suppose we have
these two variables here we can see that
they have a high correlation which means
that using these two variables is
useless
so what we can do with these we can
apply some transformation in the data to
make these variables uncorrelated in
them we can instruct the most
information that we have the next step
suppose we have the transformer data we
want to apply so this is the main topic
of these whole steps which is called the
data mined from the transformed data we
can get the patterns in how we do these
we can apply several classification
algorithms you will be able to see the
description of this video several data
mining algorithms but in this case we
can apply several algorithms such as the
K nearest neighbors or even a decision
trees application or the support vector
machines also
so these are possible algorithm data
mining algorithms or classification
algorithms that we apply to the data to
obtain patterns so the data will start
to be divided into patterns and the last
step of this process is the
interpretation of these patterns this is
not an automatic procedure the user
looks at the patterns in applied
interpretation in order to obtain the
acknowledge given by that patterns and
so the user can look at the discover
patterns try to see if there is some
redundant or irrelevant patterns and
with these things in mind he obtained
acknowledge from the data it's important
to say that we have all these green
arrows which means that we can return to
any of the previous steps that we
applied here in order to improve our
notion of patterns and also our notion
of knowledge that's why we have the such
an interconnected procedure here it's
important to say that these explanation
about knowledge discovery in databases
is based on these main reference from
Fayed in Shapiro and Smith in 1996
thanks for your attention and this is
how knowledge score in databases works