the concept of data mining is growing in
popularity in the realm of Commerce
business activities in general but it's
kind of a misconceived or misunderstood
topic and I want to give you an idea of
what data mining is all about basically
we're in the information economy and
what you have is more and more data
being generated in every aspect you can
think of every time you swipe your
grocery card when you try to get a
discount for buying whatever products
that's data being downloaded to a
database on most transactions you do
there is some sort of data download
organizations are storing processing and
analyzing data more than any time in
history and that that trend is going to
continue to grow so what is data mining
data mining is the incorporation of
quantitative methods we'll call a
mathematical methods that may include
mathematical equations algorithms some
of your your prominent methodologies are
traditional logistic regression neural
networks segmentation classification
clustering those are all methods that
utilize mathematics
data mining is applicable across
industry sectors generally wherever you
have processes wherever you have data it
is the application of these powerful
mathematical techniques in core
incorporation with some statistical type
of inference testing they call it that
will extract trends and patterns I teach
a course in NJIT data mining for
managers and I go over this the first
half of the course I give students a
very good understanding of what data
mining is because to be honest many
people don't quite understand it so if
it takes a full half of course to
provide that understanding what are
these mathematical techniques but just
as important the second half of the
course I say now you understand these
techniques now let's use them in the
business world let's apply it to
advertising and marketing effectiveness
let's apply it to e-commerce initiatives
let's apply it to even healthcare
processes supply chain processes there's
a just a number of businesses that are
that can be
mind with these techniques simply put
any organization where that has data and
it has processes can be analyzed with
data mining and the results are
extracting information actionable
information from this these data
resources that organizations can
fine-tune their the processes increase
productivity and increase efficiency so
the data mining topic this whole idea
the concept is going to grow in
popularity why because data continues to
grow think about social networking now
LinkedIn Twitter Facebook what is it
it's more data and it's data to describe
people what they do what they like who
they are when you're out buying or doing
whatever as far as using services just
conducting your daily daily lives more
and more there's data gathering and data
capturing and it's the way it is we're
in the information economy the way to
extract strategic information from that
data the data resources is with data
mining